Preliminary Guide to The Thomas Hahn Chesapeake and Ohio Canal collection, 1939-1993 MS2020
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Cumberland to Washington on the C&O Towpath by Grant Conway. July -September, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 21)
- A Walk on the Wild Side, by Toby Thompson, undated (Box 10, Folder 22)
- A Tale of the C&O Towpath. July 23, 1923 (Box 10, Folder 23)
- Lock Elevations on the C&O Canal from Rock Creek to Seneca Creek. April 19, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 24)
- Life of John Louis Washington 1878-1965. Washington County Museum of Fine Arts. Hagerstown, Md. January, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 25)
- The Patowack Canal: America's greatest eighteenth century Engineering achievement, undated (Box 10, Folder 26)
- The C&O Canal article, undated (Box 10, Folder 27)
- Injunction-Judgement-Bankruptcy. A Legal History of the C&O Canal Company by William E. Davie, undated (Box 10, Folder 28)
- Characteristics of the Boatman by Harlan Duncan, 1851-1889 (Box 10, Folder 29)
- Memories of the Old C&O Canal, nd., undated (Box 10, Folder 30)
- Boats and Boatmen, nd., undated (Box 10, Folder 31)
- Canal Talks for various canals including the C&O Canal, Erie Canal, and others., undated (Box 10, Folder 32)
- Notes for Canal Slides. Refer to Box (slides), undated (Box 10, Folder 33)
- Alexandria Gazette July 8, 1828 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- The Washington Intelligencer "Opening of the Canal" October 15, 1850 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Maryland Historical Magazine V. XLII No. 3 "A House Divided - The Conflict of Loyalties on the C&O Canal" by Walter Sanderlin. September, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- National Geographic Magazine "Washington's Historic Georgetown". April, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- The Evening Star "C&O Canal on British Television". February 19, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- The Blade-Times, caves Brunswick, Knoxville, Petersville, Points of Rocks. 58th year no. 4. Brunswick, Md February 25, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- The Washington Post "Old Foundary Preserved for Georgetown Harbor" October 24, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- The Washington Star Camera Notes October 31, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- The Washington Post "Clippers Along the C&O Canal" by Michael Kernan. August 6, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- American Canals, bulletin of the American Canal Society, undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
- The Washington Post, "An Anniversary Hike Among the Bluebells" April 12, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 11)
- Weverton, Washington Company timeline. January 5, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- The Washington Post, "Sumbitch Is More Than Just a Word Upstream on the C&O Canal Towpath". May 31, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 13)
- The Washington Post, "The Transition from Wilderness to Georgetown is a Subtle One". June 3, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 14)
- The Washington Post, "The Canal-Lovers: A Curator, a Scholar, and Two River Rats". June 2, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 15)
- The Tri-State Paper, "Canaler Remembers the Mules". September 12, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 16)
- Article regarding the C&O Canal, nd., undated (Box 11, Folder 17)
- The Washington Post, "An Interspecies Game of 'Mother May I' ", nd., undated (Box 11, Folder 18)
- Newspaper Clipping Regarding the C&O Canal, nd., undated (Box 11, Folder 19)
- Clippings from American Canal, nd, undated (Box 11, Folder 20)
- Washington Canal Failure, nd, undated (Box 11, Folder 21)
- Virginia Cavalcade "Unsuccessful Entrepreneur of the Eighteenth Century" by John Ballendine, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 22)
- Quarterly Journal of the Library of Congress "John Ballendine's Eighteenth-Century Map of Virginia" by Arthur G. Burton., 1964 (Box 11, Folder 23)
- Book by Paul H. Douglas & William K. Jones entitled Sandstone, Canals, and the Smithsonian, nd., undated (Box 11, Folder 24)
- Two articles regarding excursions and trips on the C&O Canal, nd., undated (Box 11, Folder 25)
- Two page article by George Rash "Daily Mail" managing Editor regarding Justice Douglas's role in establishing the C&O National Park., undated (Box 11, Folder 26)
- Pamphlet of Historic White's Ferry, connecting Montgomery County, Md. To Loudon County, VA. Nd, undated (Box 11, Folder 27)
- Newspaper clipping & related information on Goose Creek & Little River Navigation Co. nd., undated (Box 11, Folder 28)
- Washingtonian Magazine "The C&O Canal: Disneyland or Muirland?" by Ann Cottrell Free, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 29)
- The Blade Times, "Childhood on the C&O Canal" March 25, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 30)
- The Blade Times, "Childhood on the C&O Canal" March 11, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 31)
- "Old Photographs Bring Back Memories of Canal Life to 87 year-old resident", undated (Box 11, Folder 32)
- Towline "Not Just Barges!" Winter, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 33)
- Cumberland Times "C&O Canal Hikers" April 30, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 34)
- The Sunday Sun "Reunion Along C&O Attracts 550 Hikers" May 1, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 35)
- The Washington Post "Re-watering of all 185 Miles of C&O Canal is Proposed" April 27, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 36)
- "Reunion Along Trail" May 1, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 37)
- Baltimore Evening Sun "A lock-tender remembers the days Of the canal" November 23, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 38)
- The Washington Post "On a Barge on C&O: Canal Rats Adrift Down Memory Lane" July 20, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 39)
- Newspaper article on Thomas Hahn, undated (Box 11, Folder 40)
- The Washington Post "Hikers Back Proposal for Footpath Linking Pittsburgh, Potomac Basin" April 28, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 41)
- The Washington Post "Justice Douglas Leads C&O Canal Hike" May 8, 1960. "Douglas to Lead Reunion Hikers Down Towpath; Public Invited" May 2, 1961, 1960-1961 (Box 11, Folder 42)
- The C&O Canal: A Physical History by John Miek September, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- The Natural Cement Mills in the Upper Potomac River Valley by Thomas Hahn & Emory Kemp, nd., undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
- A interpretive planning guide for communities along scenic Byways. October, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- C&O Canal Congress Bill (original), undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Canal Songs, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Three diagrams of Freigh Barges, nd., undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Bringing life to the C&O Canal by James Holechek, nd, undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
- United States Department of the Interior Typical Canal Freight Barge blue print, scale 1/4., 1939 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Tentative Outline for C&O Canal National Historical Park Historic Resource Study compiled by: Harlan Nrau, nd., undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Georgetown Architecture: The Waterfront Potomac Lodge No. 5, nd., undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
- The American Canal Guide included area: March '72, Sept. '74, Aug. '75, Nov. '75, July '79., 1972-1979 (Box 13, Folder 7)
- The C&O and Antebellum Commerce of Old Georgetown January, 1940 (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Stabilization Study - Little Falls Skirting Canal, nd., undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Misc. maps, nd., undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Stars & Stripes Cruise II, nd., undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
- Rumsey's Contribution to Internal Waterway Improvements, nd., undated (Box 13, Folder 12)
- Virginia Canals: A Reflection of Eighteenth-Century British Engineering Practice, nd., undated (Box 13, Folder 13)
- The Rumsey Celebration, Celebrating the Two Hundredth Anniversary of Jones Rumnsy's, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 14)
- Life on The C&O Canal 1859 edited by: Ella Clark & Thomas F. Hahn, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 15)
- US Dept. of Transportation Bicentennial Catalog of Transportation Progress. October, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 16)
- 2 cardboard signs "C&O Canal" "1828-1924", undated (Box 13, Folder 17)
- Canal Talks "Introduction", undated (Box 13, Folder 18)
- American Canal Society, November 6, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 19)
- 150th Anniversary Medal of the opening of The Erie Canal, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 20)
- The Towline "A Marvel in its Day: The Georgetown Incline", nd., undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
- The Towline "Coxey's Army and the C&O Canal", 1977 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- The Towline "What's in a Seal", 1976 (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Biography & picture of W. Bollman bridge, nd., undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Picture of Great Falls (photocopy), nd., undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Photography from Herman & Stacia Miller collection photocopy of two mules stake, nd., undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Pictoral quiz printed by National Park Service, Lock #67 Shown, nd., undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Photocopy from National Park Service of Cumberland, MD, undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
- C&O Canal: Now Part of History October 11, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Color 2 page spread of a painting from the Library of Congress, nd., undated (Box 14, Folder 10)
- Building of George Washington's Monument, nd., undated (Box 14, Folder 11)
- The Towline "C&O Canal National Historical Park" V. 7 No. 1 Spring, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 12)
- Rport of John Mason to the Secretary of the Treasury January 20, 1858 (Box 14, Folder 13)
- The Lock Estiamte of the Cost to finish the Antietam, nd., undated (Box 14, Folder 14)
- "George Washington's Mountain Climbing Canal Plan is Revived" newspaper, nd., undated (Box 14, Folder 15)
- Hand-drawing around Lock #36, undated (Box 14, Folder 16)
- A Historical Memorabilla by George "Hooper" Wolfe Emphasis on the Justice Douglas C&O Canal National Park, undated (Box 14, Folder 17)
- Transportation to the Seaboard: The Central Roude from The Mississippi River to the Atlantic Ocean, by the Ohio, Kanawha and James Rivers, nd., undated (Box 14, Folder 18)
- Blueprint of the Stored Winch House at Dam No. 4, undated (Box 14, Folder 19)
- C&O Canal boats and captains after, 1892 (Box 14, Folder 20)
- Miscellaneous hand-written notes, undated (Box 14, Folder 21)
- American Canal Society, Canal Boat Construction Index, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 22)
- General Services Administration, order for copies of documents issued to vessels., undated (Box 14, Folder 23)
- Two blue-prints of C&O Canal boats, nd., undated (Box 14, Folder 24)
- Lift Locks, nd., undated (Box 14, Folder 25)
- The General Survey, physical study of C&O Canal, nd., undated (Box 14, Folder 26)
- Level Walker Reports, undated (Box 14, Folder 27)
- Check-list of birds of the District of Columbia region, 1966-1969 (Box 14, Folder 28)
- C&O Canal Hike attendees name and addresses, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 29)
- 1976 hike map, undated (Box 14, Folder 30)
- Laying the corner-stone of one of the Eastern Locks of the C&O Canal. July 4, 1829 (Box 14, Folder 31)
- Article from National park & Conservation Magazine. The Abner Cloud House the oldest original building on the C&O Canal. May, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 32)
- Elimination of Washington City Canal, undated (Box 14, Folder 33)
- Trade on the C&O Canal, undated (Box 14, Folder 34)
- Tourist & Travel Maps, V. 9 No. 3 March, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 35)
- Names of canal lock keepers, undated (Box 14, Folder 36)
  General note
  Please note: the document in this file is a list of the boats.
- Physical inventory of certain visible historic features on C&O Canal from Seneca to Cumberland, MD. August, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 37)
- Report of Captain W.M.G. McNeill on the condition of the C&O Canal, June, 1833 (Box 15, Folder 1)
- Copy of a song Dan Reeder wrote regarding the C&O Canal. March 1, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 2)
- US Engineers Office to President of the C&O Canal Board. (photocopy) September 24, 1875 (Box 15, Folder 3)
- The Black Experience, undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
- Rock Dams in the Upper Potomac by Horace P. Hobbs, Jr., undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
- United States Department of the Interior stationary with few remarks on it, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 6)
- Document written by Bill Troud regarding Harper's Ferry. January 10, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 7)
- Recommendations for the C&O Canal from Thomas Hahn, nd., undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
- Poem in honor of Orville Crowder by Thomas Hahn, nd., undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
- Arches along the C&O Canal, photocopy of pictoral document, undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
- Annual reports of internal improvement companies to the Board of Public Works. September 30, 1860 (Box 15, Folder 11)
- United States Government Memorandum from Chief of Maintenance to C&O Superintendent. June 20, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 12)
- The photographs (photocopy) of Georgetown, DC along the C&O Canal., dates vary, undated (Box 15, Folder 13)
- Four black-white pictures (photocopies) of canal boats and Georgetown, 1900 (Box 15, Folder 14)
- The Current "1920's on the C&O Canal" by Geraldine A. Nestingen., undated (Box 15, Folder 15)
- Regulations/Rules of C&O Canal, undated (Box 15, Folder 16)
- Culverts; Historical Name or letter, undated (Box 15, Folder 17)
- Pitfalls in oral history programs by Edward D Ives, nd, undated (Box 15, Folder 18)
- Oral history, nd, undated (Box 15, Folder 19)
- Photocopy of hand-written letter, 1866 (Box 15, Folder 20)
- Alleghany Portage railroad slides, January 23, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 21)
- A Bibliography on Historic sites in stream beds prepared by the American Canal Society, July, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 22)
- Filed & Stream article by Lefty Kreh, undated (Box 15, Folder 23)
- Contacts and interviews of the C&O Canal, undated (Box 15, Folder 24)
- General Laws. 51st Council, 1853 (Box 15, Folder 25)
- Index of the major structures of the C&O Canal, undated (Box 15, Folder 26)
- C&O Canal, locks on the canal, undated (Box 15, Folder 27)
- Culverts on the C&O Canal, undated (Box 15, Folder 28)
- A Beginner's Guide to Canoeing on the "Upper Potomac's" by John Seabury Thomson, undated (Box 15, Folder 29)
- The Black American Experience "Seminar Series for Interpreters National Capital Region National Park Service", undated (Box 15, Folder 30)
- Supreme Court of the District of Columbia, United States Of America vs. Martin F. Marris, nd, undated (Box 15, Folder 31)
- Cabin John Bridge, C&O Canal, nd, undated (Box 15, Folder 32)
- C&O Canal Eastern Section, Canals No. 6 Flat drawing by Wm. B. Acket January 18, 1939 (Box 15, Folder 33)
- United States Department of the Interior, National Park Service. Memorandum to Mr. Gillen. January 19, 1939 (Box 15, Folder 34)
- Miscellaneous documents relating to the C&O Canal, nd, undated (Box 15, Folder 35)
- Seminar Workshop program, undated (Box 15, Folder 36)
- Diagram of Lock #35 and #36 of the C&O Canal, undated (Box 15, Folder 37)
- Suter's Tavern by Cornelius W. Heine. Chief, Public Use Branch. National Capitol Parks, undated (Box 15, Folder 38)
- Water colors of the early canal buildings, undated (Box 15, Folder 39)
- Georgetown Canal inclined plane diagram, undated (Box 15, Folder 40)
- Canal boats, undated (Box 15, Folder 41)
- Book concerning Canals in the United States and Canada, undated (Box 15, Folder 42)
- Interpretive themes for the National Capital Region National Park Service January 12, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 43)
- Miscellaneous papers, undated (Box 15, Folder 44)
- 4 pieces of a booklet, undated (Box 15, Folder 45)
- Appendix A: A Synthesic of the History of the Potomac River valley by: Walter S. Sanderlin, undated (Box 15, Folder 46)
- Fort Lesley J. McNair on historical landmark, undated (Box 15, Folder 47)
- C&O Canal Company shareholder bonds. Denominations: $5, $10, $20. (copy), 1840 (Box 15, Folder 48)
- Waterways World "America's Inland Waterways The C&O Canal", nd., undated (Box 15, Folder 49)
- Potomac River basin, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Green Ridge Hiking Trail, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Sketches of Stone Structures, undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Sketch of Antietam Cement Works Kilns, undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Sketch of Canal barge, undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Sketch of Battle at Dam No. 4, undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Round Top Cement Company, 1907 (Box 16, Folder 7)
- Sketch of Godey Lime Kilns, undated (Box 16, Folder 8)
- Sketch of Alexandria Canal Aqueduct, undated (Box 16, Folder 9)
- The last boat down the C&O Canal Cumberland, MD., 1936 (Box 16, Folder 10)
- And the floods came! March 17, 1936 (Box 16, Folder 11)
- Lock 44 and Paw Paw Tunnel, undated (Box 16, Folder 12)
- Cliff areas above Dam No. 5 and Four Locks, undated (Box 16, Folder 13)
- Aqueduct of the Chesapeake and Ohio Canal, at the mouth of the Monocacy, undated (Box 16, Folder 14)
- Gun Owner's Creed, undated (Box 16, Folder 15)
- Sketch of Point of Rocks Train Station, undated (Box 16, Folder 16)
- Location of canal terminus in Cumberland, MD, undated (Box 16, Folder 17)
- Two Locks, undated (Box 16, Folder 18)
- Stop Gate Dam 4, undated (Box 16, Folder 19)
- Licking Creek Aqueduct, undated (Box 16, Folder 20)
- Building along canal, undated (Box 16, Folder 21)
- Inside Monocacy Aqueduct, undated (Box 16, Folder 22)
- Salty Dog Saloon, undated (Box 16, Folder 23)
- Sketch of building. n.d, undated (Box 16, Folder 24)
- Berli, undated (Box 16, Folder 25)
- Grant information, undated (Box 16, Folder 26)
- Yesteryear on the canal, undated (Box 16, Folder 27)
- Typical hard working couple who made the canal their life, undated (Box 16, Folder 28)
- Bridge over the C&O Canal, 1850 ca. (Box 16, Folder 29)
- Cumberland loading wharf, undated (Box 16, Folder 30)
- View from the C&O Canal basin, Cumberland, MD, 1910 ca. (Box 16, Folder 31)
- Sketch of C&O Canal Tunnel at Paw Paw., 1963 (Box 16, Folder 32)
- Sketch of a Dutch canal, undated (Box 16, Folder 33)
- Sketch of an old English lock, undated (Box 16, Folder 34)
- Close-up of stonework, undated (Box 16, Folder 35)
- Sketch of Williamsport aqueduct, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 36)
- Sketch of detail of Glen Echo Carousel, undated (Box 16, Folder 37)
- Sketch of detail of Inlet Lock at Dam No. 4, undated (Box 16, Folder 38)
- Sketch of Old Town, undated (Box 16, Folder 39)
- Sketch of Sheperdstown, WV cement kilns and kiln openings, undated (Box 16, Folder 40)
- Sketch of the Lockkeeper's House, undated (Box 16, Folder 41)
- Sketch of a Chinese canal, undated (Box 16, Folder 42)
- Sketch of Tonoloway Aqueduct, undated (Box 16, Folder 43)
- Bibliography of Spring gap -Cumberland area, undated (Box 16, Folder 44)
- C&O Canal Association 25th Annual Reunion Hike, undated (Box 16, Folder 45)
- Illustration of old bridge and mill, Antietam-Antietam RollingMill-Burnside Bridge, undated (Box 16, Folder 46)
- Illustration of the campaign on the Potomac-Unsuccessful attempt of the rebels to destroy dam No. 5 on the Upper Potomac near Williamsport, MD. December, 1861 (Box 16, Folder 47)
- Illustration of the rebels destroying the Chesapeeake and Ohio Canal. Harper's Weekly., 1864 (Box 16, Folder 48)
- Letter to Mr. Hutton about C&O Canal. September 1, 1894 (Box 16, Folder 49)
- Potomac Canal Report, November 5, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 50)
- Notebook, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Notebook, undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
- C&O Canal NHP, Development Concept Plan. Great Falls, MD, undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
- "Come See Williamsport Maryland" brochure, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
- Abner Cloud House, undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Plan of cabin, C&O Canal boat, undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
- "Bull Frizzel's Pluck" Washington Post, June 27, 1897 (Box 17, Folder 7)
- "One of the Barns at Peirce Mill" with the Rambler. The Sunday Star. February 20, 1916 (Box 17, Folder 8)
- Peirce Family, undated (Box 17, Folder 9)
- The Collecting Basin, undated (Box 17, Folder 10)
- Cresap Mill at Old Town, MD, undated (Box 17, Folder 11)
- The L'Enfant Plan, undated (Box 17, Folder 12)
- Latrobe's details of a lock, undated (Box 17, Folder 13)
- Washington Canal, undated (Box 17, Folder 14)
- Balloon view of the city, undated (Box 17, Folder 15)
- Conversation with Cecil Jamison, undated (Box 17, Folder 16)
- Paw Paw Tunnel, undated (Box 17, Folder 17)
- Washington City Canal, undated (Box 17, Folder 18)
- Eastern Extension of C&O Canal, undated (Box 17, Folder 19)
- Peirce family, undated (Box 17, Folder 20)
- Images and text of parts of canal, undated (Box 17, Folder 21)
- Level 0, undated (Box 17, Folder 22)
- City of Cumberland, MD, undated (Box 17, Folder 23)
- Repairs to Stone Dam across the Potomac River. Brookmont, MD, undated (Box 17, Folder 24)
- Restoration of Hydraulic Structures, Fuse plug, undated (Box 17, Folder 25)
- Flood conditions, undated (Box 17, Folder 26)
- Survey of the Proposed C&O Canal Parkway, undated (Box 17, Folder 27)
- Pictures and text of repairs to canal, undated (Box 17, Folder 28)
- Help needed to bring back the canal, undated (Box 17, Folder 29)
- Canal barge boatman and wife, undated (Box 17, Folder 30)
- Lock 3, Georgetown, undated (Box 17, Folder 31)
- Roundtop Kilns, undated (Box 17, Folder 32)
- Paw paw tunnel, undated (Box 17, Folder 33)
- A loaded freight boat on the C&O Canal, undated (Box 17, Folder 34)
- Broadcast of W.M. Portman Club C&O Canal club shows Justice Douglas, undated (Box 17, Folder 35)
- Repair of feeder canal in vicinity of Lock 6, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 36)
- Plate showing property and levels at Feeder Gats, Lock No. 5, 1936 (Box 17, Folder 37)
- Plate of survey of the C&O Canal form Stone No. 12 to Stone No. 1 of the Old Potomac Canal, Md., undated (Box 17, Folder 38)
- Property map of the C&O Canal Company, updated to, 1895 (Box 17, Folder 39)
- Plate of survey of the C&O from the mix tract to stone no. 12, undated (Box 17, Folder 41)
- Lock 11 to Lock 15, undated (Box 17, Folder 42)
- House at Lock 37, undated (Box 17, Folder 43)
- Alexandria Canal, draft, undated (Box 17, Folder 44)
- Maryland Historical Magazine vol. 81, no.4, article"The Tidewater End of the Chesapeake and Ohio Canal", William M. Franklin, Winter, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 1)
- Springtime along the C&O Canal, Kenneth G. Knouf, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
- Barry-Berlin-Brunswick: A Brief History, Dorothy U. Strathern, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 3)
- 184 Miles of Adventure Hiker's Guide to the C&O Canal, Baltimore Area Council-Boy Scouts of America, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 4)
- Blue Ridge Voyages Volume Four An Illustrated Canoe Log of the Shenandoah River and its South Fork, Louis J. Matacia and Owen S. Cecil III, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 5)
- C&O Canal Memories, Lavenia Waskey Brust, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 6)
- The Community of Four Locks, Mike Mastranggelo, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 7)
- A Collection of Maps of the Chesapeake and Ohio Canal, William Clague, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 8)
- Maryland Historical Magazine vol. 55, no.2 June 1960 article "Life on the C&O Canal: 1859", Ella E. Clark, undated (Box 18, Folder 9)
- Administrative Policies for Natural Areas of the National Park System, NPS, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 10)
- National Geographic vol. 171, no.6 article "The Patowmack Canal: Waterway that Lead to the Constitution", Wilbur E. Garrett, June, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 11)
- National Geographic vol. 117, no.3 article "Waterway to Washington, the C&O Canal", Jay Johnston, March, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 12)
- Man and Nature in the National Parks: Reflections on Policy, F. Fraser Darling and Noel D. Eichhorn, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 13)
- Hey-Ey-Ey, Lock!: Adventure on the Chesapeake & Ohio Canal, Morris Fradin, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 14)
- Chesapeake and Ohio Canal National Historic Park District of Columbia/Maryland General Plan. January, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 15)
- Samantha Goes to Georgetown on the C&O Canal, Barbara Winslow, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 16)
- The Chesapeake and Ohio Canal Celebrates 150 Years (1828-1978) (Box 18, Folder 17)
- A Collection of Maps of the Chesapeake and Ohio Canal, Potomac Area American Youth Hostels, Inc., 1967 (Box 18, Folder 18)
- Georgetown Architecture The Waterfront Selections from the Historic American Buildings Survey Number 4, undated (Box 18, Folder 19)
- Brookmont Unremembered Days, Grant Conway, October, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 20)
- Organizing Archival Records: A Practical Method of Arrangement and Description for Small Archives, David W. Carmichael, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 21)
- Pennsylvania Transportation History: A Supplement, William H. Shank, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 22)
- C&O Canal: The making of a Park, Barry Mackintosh, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 23)
- Valleys of History vol. 4 no. 4 article "The Paw Paw Tunnel - Engineering Marvel of 1850" Autumn, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 24)